JYOTI DNYANESHWAR PAWAR

Senior Engineer: Product Development

Pune Maharashtra. Jyotipawar167@gmail.com +91-9766166775

PROFILE

Versatile offers over 5 years of experience in the IT industry working in Xamarin forms development. I have worked in agile development, and I wish to be a part of your organization where I can utilize my technical skills in development and expand my domains as well as personal skills for acceleration of organization's growth and reputation.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology, (B. Tech)

Aug 2012 - Jun 2015

Computer Science, University of Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar Marathwada.

Diploma, Jun 2009 - Aug 2015

Computer Science and Engineering, University of MSBTE Mumbai.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: C# .Net

Mobile Technology: Xamarin Forms, MAUI, Unity3D

Database: SOLite

Software's & DevOps Tools: Visual Studio, Git-Hub, Postman

Cloud Computing: Microsoft Azure

WORK EXPERIENCE & PROJECTS

Harman Connected Services Pvt. Ltd.

May 2022 - 28 Feb 2023

Senior Engineer (Product Development)

- 1. Smart Digital Trial Room
 - Build on Unity3D with Azure Kinect DK camera
 - Implemented cross-platform functionality by integrating Unity3D Model into Xamarin MAUI
 - Analyze problems and define/Implement solutions.
 - Digitally we can change and check apparel on human body in the mall or any clothing shop, for this develop
 - Used Microsoft azure Kinect camera and Azure Kinect Body Tracking SDK to recognizehand and body gesture
 - Build 3d on CGTrader
 - Responsible for developing AR module

SA Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Jun 2021- Apr 2022

Developer - Mobile Applications

- 1. ABB Mobile App
 - Xamarin forms with expertise in MAUI (Multi-platform App UI) framework.
 - Build for capturing machine details as if has defect

- Responsible for analysis, design, implementation, code review and deployment
- Involve in writing Business logic
- Responsible for creating Dynamic user interface
- Used collection view, grid view to connect with SQLite database
- Responsible for multiple testing phases

Alike Thought Pvt. Ltd.

Aug 2020 - Apr 2021

Senior Developer.

- Xamarin forms technology
- Build for capturing machine details as if has defect
- Responsible for analysis, design, implementation, code review and deployment
- Involve in writing Business logic
- Responsible for creating Dynamic user interface
- Used collection view, grid view to connect with SQLite database
- Responsible for multiple testing phases

HolidayMe Pvt. Ltd.

Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

Technical Consultant - Xamarin.

- 1. Xamarin forms technology and .net.
- 2. Product base app was for travel purpose such booking hotels and flights
- 3. Designed the architecture for the application to be cross-platform compatible
- 4. Used location service, localization for data translation
- 5. For bookings used payment integration services

Wiriya Technology Pvt. Ltd.

Jun 2018 - Dec 2019

Senior Mobile Application Developer.

- 1. Xamarin forms technology
- 2. Responsible for all the phases of software development
- 3. Gathering business requirement, design and implementation
- 4. Experienced with Agile and Scrum methodologies using JIRA
- 5. Performed unity testing debugging and rigorous problem solving
- 6. Used MVVM pattern to design the application

ParalleMinds Technology

May 2016 - Dec 2017

Software developer trainee.

- 1. Xamarin forms technology
- 2. Learned Xamarin forms.
- 3. Responsible for creating small modules and POCs
- 4. Created business logic for calculator application
- 5. Used stack view, Auto layout and size classes to create responsive and efficient user interface
- 6. Used LINQ queries for SQLite database for mobile platform

SGHI-TECH Jan 2015 - Apr 2016

Trainee.

- 1. .Net web development
- 2. Gather detailed use cases and requirements through regular on-site visits, virtual meetings and customer advisory board sessions.
- 3. Translated technical specifications into detailed product requirements.
- 4. Strong understanding of system reliability, scalability, and security measures.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES & WORK ACHIEVEMENT

- Won first prize for Digital Trail Room project in Hackathon Retail Competition, conducted in Harman Connected Services.
- Event Manager in the college for Techfest festival.
- President in Module development in ParallelMinds Pvt Ltd organization.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Collaborative
- Continuous learning
- Project Execution

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name Jyoti Dnyaneshwar Pawar

Date of Birth 16 August 1992

Passport Z5860889

Driving License no MH21 20190000752